Preliminary Inventory of the Diane Ravitch Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Course taking, 1984-1993 and undated (Box-folder 25: 4)
  Clipping, memoranda, report, and related materials
- States, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  Brochure, clippings, proposed revisions, and working papers
- Scholars - John Ralph and others paper, undated (Box-folder 25: 6)
- History, 1995 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  Article, book, clippings, and letter
- Geography, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  Memoranda, note, and printed matter
- Mathematics, 1990-1992 and undated (Box-folder 25: 9)
  Bibliography, clipping, conference call, correspondence, memoranda, and report
- Mathematics, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  Clippings, memoranda, and telecommunication project
- Delivery, 1993 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  Clipping, outline for a paper, report, and summary
- Office of Educational Research and Improvement (OERI), 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 26: 3)
  Article, clipping, comment, memoranda, note, press conference, and statement
- Teachers, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 26: 4)
  Article, chart, memoranda, note, report, and study
- Sykes, Gary, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  Papers
- Social studies, 1964-1983 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  Booklet and report
- Oral History project, 1986 (Box-folder 26: 7)
- Society etc., 1988 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  Clipping
- Soviet Education, 1986 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  Photocopy of an article on Soviet Education from a journal
- Sowell, Thomas, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Teacher education, 1948-1985 (Box-folder 27: 4-5)
  Photocopies of others' writings and study
- Stedman, Lawrence C. Book reviews, 1995 (Box-folder 27: 6)
- Teachers, 1980-1995 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  Journal, newsletter, paper, and report
- Teachers College, Columbia University, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  Letters and memorandum regarding renewal of appointment
- Standards international, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  London and East Anglian group, Canada, France, Germany, Britain, New Zealand, China, Japan, Israel, Republic of Korea, United States, and Netherlands. Articles, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and summary of a paper
- International studies, 1989-1993 and undated (Box-folder 27: 10)
  Article, clippings, memoranda, note, and related materials
- Stanford University, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  Article, campus newspapers, clippings, and transcripts of a television talk show
- Bradley Commission, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  Clippings, comments, and survey
- California, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  Clippings, letter, newsletter, and statewide listing of courses offered
- Portland, Oregon African American Education, 1990 (Box-folder 28: 4)
- African American males, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  Clipping, correspondence, memoranda, news bulletin, and report
- Book project, 1984-1989 and undated (Box-folder 28: 6-7)
  Bibliography, brochure, clippings, correspondence, flyer, form letters, newsletter, and related materials
- Affirmative Action, 1992-1995 and undated (Box-folder 28: 8)
  Articles, clippings, newsletter, and speech by President William Jefferson Clinton
- Afrocentrism, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 28: 9)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, newsletter, and statement
- National Governors Association, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  Project update and report
- California, 1985-1995 and undated (Box-folder 29: 2-4)
  Agenda for the twenty first century, article by Diane Ravitch assessmentoutline, chart, clippings. correspondence, History-Social Science curriculum, list of recommended readings, memoranda, note, report, and schedule
- California curriculum, 1987-1989 and undated (Box-folder 29: 5-6)
  Clipping, instructional materials evaluation quality journal, reports, and related materials
- California curriculum, 1986-1989 and undated (Box-folder 30: 1)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, list of recommended books, newsletter, report, and related materials
- College Board Examination - History, 1901-1941 (Box-folder 30: 2-4)
  Photocopies
- California textbooks, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  Clipping and report
- Children's literature, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 30: 6)
- California curriculum, 1986-1989 and undated (Box-folder 31: 1-2)
  Articles,clippings, correspondence, journal, memoranda, report, and related materials
- Curriculum of inclusion, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 31: 3-5)
  Correspondence, clippings, memoranda, minutes of a meeting, news release, printed matter, and report
- "Common Knowledge,", undated (Box-folder 32: 1)
  Draft chapters
- Critiques, undated (Box-folder 32: 2)
  Article by Maxine Greene
- Cultural literacy, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  Address, articles, and correspondence
- Conference idea for cultural literacy, 1967-1988 and undated (Box-folder 32: 4)
  Articles, brochure, clippings, notes, and remarks
- Catholic schools, 1991 and undated (Box-folder 32: 5)
  Notes and speech delivered by Diane Ravitch on "Catholic Education and Occam's Razor," Eighth Annual Seton-Neumann Lecture. Includes news release
- Cartoons, 1992 and undated (Box-folder 32: 6)
- Walberg, Herbert J. Article, 1984 (Box-folder 32: 7)
- Washington, D.C., 1974-1995 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  Clippings, letter, report, and summary of school enrollment
- Western civilization Articles, 1995 (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Whole language Clippings, 1995 (Box-folder 32: 10)
- Wilmington, Delaware Reports, 1975 (Box-folder 32: 11)
- Wisconsin Reports, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 32: 12)
- White House Memorandum, 1991 (Box-folder 32: 13)
- Women's Educational Equity Act (WEEA) Program Memoranda, 1991 (Box-folder 32: 14)
- Responses - What Do Our 17-Year-Olds Know?, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 32: 15)
  Article, correspondence, and memorandum
- Women's issues, 1972-1993 and undated (Box-folder 32: 16)
  Articles, brochures, and notes
- Women's issues - Sexism, 1974-1982 and undated (Box-folder 32: 17)
  Brochure, clippings, journal, and report
- Women's history, 1988 and undated (Box-folder 33: 1)
  Brochure, flyer, and newsletter
- Workforce 2000 Memorandum, 1991 (Box-folder 33: 2)
- Curriculum of inclusion, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 33: 3-4)
  Agenda and minutes of a meeting, letters, and memorandum. Includes an articleby Diane Ravitch, "Multiculturalism in the Curriculum," presented to Manhattan Institute, 1989
- Examinations in comprehensive social studies, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  Booklets
- Hereditary Intelligence Tests, Clipping and miscellany, 1993 (Box-folder 33: 6)
- National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), 1974-1984 and undated (Box-folder 33: 7-8)
  Article, newsletters, reports, and survey
- Teachers University - New York City, 1940-1978 and undated (Box-folder 33: 9)
  Article, letter, and clippings
- Transition memorandum and report, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 33: 10)
- Truman, Harry, 1947-1979 (Box-folder 33: 11)
  Clippings and list of citations on the subject of President Truman's actions on civil rights
- Vinovskis, Maris A., 1993-1995 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  Publishing agreement with Johns Hopkins University Press for editing with Diane Ravitch a volume and writings
- Kirp, David L., Michael W. Kirst, and Reed Ueda writings, undated (Box-folder 34: 2)
- Viteritti, Joseph P., 1994-1995 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  Bibliographical index, letter, topical outline, writings of Diane Ravitch, including one with Joseph Viteritti, and related materials
- Texas, 1992-1994 and undated (Box-folder 34: 4-5)
  Brochure, guide to public school performance reporting, journal, letter, reports, and related materials Article
- Testing (Box 35)
  - Critics, 1991-1993 and undated (Box-folder 35: 1)
    Clippings, newsletter, report, and related materials
  - Emerson Elliott, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 35: 2-4)
    Articles, clipping, correspondence, memoranda, news release, notes,study, working paper, and related materials
  - Skills and scope, 1975-1977 and undated (Box-folder 35: 5)
    Clippings, report, and statistical data
  - Sleeper - Civic culture essay, 1993 (Box-folder 35: 6)
- Social studies (Box 35)
  - Maryland, 1990 and undated (Box-folder 35: 7)
    Reports on Maryland School Performance Assessment Program and curricular framework
  - Massachusetts Report, 1988 (Box-folder 35: 8)
- Writings (Box 35)
  - Notes, articles and clippings, 1991-1993 and undated (Box-folder 35: 9)
  - Choice, undated (Box-folder 36: 1)
    "Somebody's Children: Educational Opportunity for all American Children," chapter 3
  - Responses-- What Do Our 17-Year-Olds Know?, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 36: 2)
    Clippings, correspondence, memoranda, and related materials
- Social studies
  - Detroit, Michigan--Elementary schools, 1995-1996 and undated (Box-folder 36: 3-4)
    Correspondence, memoranda, and reports
  - Curriculum, 1985 and undated (Box-folder 36: 5)
    Letter, outline, program, and report
- Writings: What Do Our 17-Year-Olds Know? Reviews, 1987 (Box-folder 36: 6)
- Journal, news release, paper, printed matter, report, and reviews, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 37: 1)
- Articles by Diane Ravitch, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 37: 2)
  Bulletin, clippings, and correspondence
- Reviews, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 37: 3)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and related materials. Includes reviews of American Reader
- Speeches, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 37: 4)
- Personal, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 37: 5)
  Flyer, messages of congratulation, correspondence, and note
- General, 1988 (Box-folder 37: 6)
- History, 1992 (Box-folder 37: 7)
- Speeches, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 37: 8)
  Conference paper, lecture, memoranda, remarks, speech, and statement
- Self-Esteem, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  Articles, cartoons, and form letter
- Sewall, Gilbert T. letter and report, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 38: 2)
- Seminars on History, I and II, 1978-1980 and undated (Box-folder 38: 3-4)
  Biographical information, correspondence, financial records, flyer, list of students, memoranda, and related materials
- Sex education clippings, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 38: 5)
- Shanker, Albert, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 38: 6)
  Article, clippings, and newsletter
- Shafer, Ingrid H., 1989 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  Cover letter and essay
- Shakespeare, William, 1932-1960 (Box-folder 38: 8)
- Sizer, Theodore R., 1992-1993 (Box-folder 38: 9)
- Social Studies, 1967-1996 and undated (Box-folder 38: 10-11)
  Articles, comparison chart, clippings, memoranda, reports, and related materials
- Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), 1971-1995 and undated (Box-folder 39: 1-3)
  Articles, booklet, chart, clippings, memoranda, newsletter, printed matter, report, statistical data, study, table, and related materials
- Sawhill, Isabel V., 1995 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Letter, 1988 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Finance, 1977-1982 and undated (Box-folder 39: 6)
    Booklet, clippings, and report
  - Education, 1975-1993. Clippings and newsletter (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - The Schools We Deserve: Reflections on the Educational Crisis of Our Time, Reviews, 1985- 1988 (Box-folder 39: 8)
  - Science, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 39: 9)
    Clipping and printed matter
  - Science books, 1986-1989 and undated (Box-folder 39: 10)
    Clippings, notes, and research guide
  - School size, 1994 (Box-folder 39: 11)
    Note
  - School-to-Work, 1994 (Box-folder 39: 12)
    Article and clipping
  - Secondary education, undated (Box-folder 39: 13)
    Article by Diane Ravitch
- Schwarzenegger, Arnold, 1992 (Box-folder 40: 1)
- Schlesinger, Arnold, Jr., 1994 (Box-folder 40: 2)
  Lecture
- Open Court Publishing Company, 1988 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  Article, letters, and memorandum
- Office of Educational Research and Improvement (OERI) -Personal, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  Calendar, correspondence, list of excepted service employees, memoranda, note, proposal, and survey
- Transition. Note, undated (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - General, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Readability formulas, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - Readers, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - Textbooks, 1929-1995 (Box-folder 40: 9)
    Clippings and notes
- Right to reprint an article, "Don't Subject History to Political Revamping," granted by Diane Ravitch, 1991 (Box-folder 40: 10)
  Copy of the article and a cover letter
- Diane Ravitch - Reviews of The Revisionists Revised, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 40: 11-12)
  Author's questionnaire and statement, clippings, correspondence, notes, and related materials
- Connors, Eugene T., 1979 (Box-folder 40: 13)
  Book
- Hamline University, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1975-1996 and undated (Box-folder 40: 14)
  Notes
- Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), 1975-1996 and undated (Box-folder 40: 15-17)
  Article, brochure, clipping, memoranda, newsletter, news release, printed copy, report, review of SAT score trends,statement, and tables
- Diane Ravitch (Box-folder 41:)
  - Quoted, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 41: 1-2)
    Articles, bulletin, clippings, correspondence, memoranda, newsletters, news release, and remarks
  - Articles, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 41: 3-4)
    Includes clippings, memoranda, news articles, newsletters, and related materials
  - Speeches, 1986-1992 and undated (Box-folder 41: 5-6)
    Includes newsletters, notes, and report
  - Speeches, 1985-1992 and undated (Box-folder 42: 1-2)
    Includes notes
  - Articles, 1987-1989 and undated (Box-folder : 3)
  - Clippings about Diane Ravitch, 1990 (Box-folder 42: 4)
- Review of What Do Our 17-Year-Olds Know?, 1987 (Box-folder 42: 5)
- Review of "Education and the Public Good," Review, 1988 summer (Box-folder 42: 6)
  Includes articles by others
- Diane Ravitch and Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., 1990 (Box-folder 42: 7)
  Statement of the Committee of Scholars in Defense of History, written by Diane Ravitch and Arthur Schlesinger, Jr.
- Secondary education article, undated (Box-folder 42: 8)
- Self-Esteem article, 1990 (Box-folder 42: 9)
- Speeches and articles, 1987-1995 and undated (Box-folder 42: 10-11)
- Files from Office of Educational Research and Improvement (OERI), 1991-1993 and undated (Box-folder 42: 12)
  Correspondence, memoranda, and proposal
- Articles, 1990-1993 and undated (Box-folder 43: 1)
- Files from the Office of Assistant Secretary of Education and Counselor to the Secretary of Education, 1991-1993 and undated (Box-folder 43: 2)
  Letters, memoranda, and note
- "Education and Public Good" article, 1988 (Box-folder 43: 3)
- Article, Perspectives, 1991 (Box-folder 43: 4)
- Reviews and speech on "Erosion of History" delivered at the Annual Meeting of the Organization of American Historians and National Council on Public History, 1987 and undated (Box-folder 43: 5)
- Reviews, articles, including on "Evolution of Schools,", 1976-1987 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  Includes clippings
- Poland, 1990 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  Brochure, lecture, newsletter, and remarks
- Speeches and articles, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 43: 8)
- Reviews, 1972-1989 and undated (Box-folder 44: 1)
- Reviews and article, 1974-1995 (Box-folder 44: 2)
- Race, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 3)
- Articles, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 4)
- Review of The American Reader, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 5)
- Reviews, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 6)
- Miscellany, 1983-1984 and undated (Box-folder 44: 7)
- Writing by others, 1999 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - Undated (Box-folder 44: 9)
  - 1985-1989 (Box-folder 44: 10-14)
  - 1990 (Box-folder 45: 1-4)
  - 1991 (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - 2003 (Box-folder 45: 6)
  - Agreements with publishers, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 45: 7)
- Clippings, 1963-1991 and undated (Box-folder 45: 8)
  Includes biographical information about Diane Ravitch for Who's Who in America
- Notes, undated (Box-folder 45: 9)
- Reviews, 1999 and undated (Box-folder 45: 10)
- Writings by Diane Ravitch, undated (Box-folder 45: 11)
- Testimony, 2003 (Box-folder 45: 12)
- Writings by others, 1989 and undated (Box-folder 45: 13)
- Miscellany, 1988-1991 and undated (Box-folder 45: 14)
- Bradley Commission on History in Schools, 1980-1991 and undated (Box-folder 45: 15-16)
  Article, brochure, clippings, comments, correspondence, flyer, memoranda, minutes of meeting, news release, printed matter, report, study, and summary
- Multiculturalism, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 46: 1-5)
  Article, clipping, correspondence, excerpts from conversation, lecture notes, memoranda, newsletter, printed matter, report, and transcripts of television program
- Multiculturalism - Afrocentrism, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 46: 6)
  Article by Diane Ravitch, clipping, newsletter, and printed matter
- Sidney Hook, 1949-1983 (Box-folder 46: 7)
  Correspondence, photocopy of article, and flyer
- Multiculturalism - Government, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 47: 1)
  Articles by Diane Ravitch and others, clipping, conference paper, correspondence, memoranda, newsletter, and report
- National Academy of Education, 1978-1979 and undated (Box-folder 47: 2)
  Article, clipping, correspondence, list of office holders and members, memoranda, news release, and report
- Speeches, 1982-1995 and undated (Box-folder 47: 3-4)
  Includes notes and printed matter
- Houston, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 47: 5)
- Coleman Report, 1966-1990 (Box-folder 47: 6)
  Articles, clipping,correspondence, journal, memoranda, paper, printed matter, and report
- Coleman Report, 1966-1990 (Box-folder 48: 1)
- Multiculturalism, 1986-1994 and undated (Box-folder 48: 2-3)
  Article, clippings, correspondence, and research reports
- Multiculturalism - Afrocentrism, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 48: 4)
  Articles, brochure, clipping, journal, and news release
- Cremin, Lawrence A., 1972-1975 and undated (Box-folder 48: 5)
  Articles, clippings, and notes
- Bilingual education, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 48: 6)
  Guidelines for the Education of Limited English Proficient Caribbean Creole speaking students in New York State, and study
- Speech materials, 1992-1994 and undated (Box-folder 48: 7)
  Articles, clippings, minutes of meeting, newsletter, note, position paper, printed matter, and report
- Diane Ravitch, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 49: 1)
  Memoranda, note, remarks, and speeches
- Miscellany, 1989-1990 and undated (Box-folder 49: 2)
  Article, brochure of National Council for History Education, Inc., correspondence, flyer, memoranda, newsletter, statement of the Committee of Scholars in Defense of History, and proposal for the National Council for History in the Schools
- Social Studies - Elementary Course of Study, 1930s-1970s, 1986 (Box-folder 49: 3)
  Article, clipping, correspondence, and remarks. Includes photocopies
- Standards - English, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 49: 4)
  Article, clippings, and printed matter
- Hanna, Paul R., 1915-1987 (Box-folder 49: 5)
  Articles, clippings, and related materials
- Multiculturalism, 1989-1990 and undated (Box-folder 49: 6)
  Correspondence, comments, memoranda, and minutes of meeting
- Gender, 1992 (Box-folder 49: 7)
- History - Standard, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, journal, memoranda, minutes of meeting, newsletter, news release, note, printed matter, remarks, report, and statement
- Diane Ravitch, 1986-2006 and undated (Box-folder 50:4-6)
  Articles, correspondence, flyer, notes, paper, speeches, and remarks
- Leigh Bill, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  Article, contract, correspondence, and itinerary
- Speeches and articles, 1974-1998 and undated (Box-folder 51: 2-4)
  Includes brochure, clipping, notes, and printed matter
- Catholic schools, 1988-1997 and undated (Box-folder 51: 5)
  Article, clippings, memoranda, and statistical data
- Diane Ravitch - Unpublished articles, 1958-1967 and undated (Box-folder 51: 6)
  Notes and report
- Wellesley College Newsletters, 1958 (Box-folder 52: 1)
- Carnegie Corporation, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  Articles, correspondence,interview, memoranda, newsletter, proposal, and report
- Speeches, 1988-1999 and undated (Box-folder 52:3-5)
  Articles, brochure, clippings, correspondence, flyer, note, report, and related materials
- Journals, 1977-2006 (Box-folder 52: 6)
- Writings and reviews, 1977-2002 (Box-folder 52: 7)
- Miscellany, 1988-2007 and undated (Box-folder 52: 8)
  Booklets, conference schedule, flyers, and report
- Curriculum - History and Social Sciences, 1957-2001 and undated (Box-folder 53: 1-3)
  Articles, booklet, brochure, bulletin, clippings, correspondence, handbook, journal, list of printed ethnic materials, memoranda, newsletter, note, and report
- Wellesley College - Paper prepared for History by Diane Silvers (Ravitch), 1960 (Box-folder 53: 4)
- Giuliani, Rudolph W., Mayor, City of New York, 2001 (Box-folder 53: 5)
  Greetings
- Articles, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 53: 6)
- Diane Ravitch's notes for The Great School Wars, 1974 (Box-folder 53:7-8)
- New York Times Magazine, 1985 (Box-folder 54: 1)
- Articles and reviews, 1955-1997 and undated (Box-folder 54: 2)
- Reprint agreements, 1978-1996 and undated (Box-folder 54: 3)
  Letters to the publishers
- Teaching materials, 1973-1985 and undated (Box-folder 54: 4)
  Includes class roster, course outlines, grading, lecture, notes, proposal for a new course, reading list, and related materials
- Poland, 1990 (Box-folder 54: 5)
  Includes articles, clippings, collection of photographs and post cards from 1898-1916, entry ticket to parliament, and lecture in both English and Polish versions
- Diane Ravitch (Box 54)
  - Personal, 1971-1997 and undated (Box-folder 54: 6)
    Includes announcements of lectures, appointment letters, biographical information, certificate of successfully completing course in French language, copies of President William Jefferson Clinton's State of the Union addresses signed by him, 1995 and 1997, defense of her dissertation, note of admission to Teachers College, Columbia University, and schedule
  - Speech announcement about Diane Ravitch's book, Left Back: A Century of Battles over School Reform, 2000, at a reception, 2001, and a flyer offering salute to her in celebration of her outstanding contributions to the cause of school reform, 2001 and undated (Box 55)
    Includes letters paying tribute to her
- Diane Ravitch - Writings and speeches (Box 56)
  - American Reader, 1983-2001 and undated (Box-folder 56: 1)
    Includes bibliography, brochures for lecture and speech, confirmation hearings of David Lilienthal, lecture, list of books, notes, request for an NYU-Internet account and related materials
  - "Education and Culture in a Free Society," speech, delivered in Hungary, Czechoslovakia, Poland, and Romania, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 2)
  - "The Global Democratic Revolution," keynote address, California Department of Education, California, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 3)
  - "Japan's Smart Schools," The New Republic, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 4)
  - Multiculturalism Articles in The Key Reporter, the Chronicle of Higher Education, Clipboard, and Perspectives, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 56: 5)
  - Packet on multiculturalism, 1990-1991 and undated (Box-folder 56: 6)
    Articles, clippings, report, speech, and related materials
  - Articles, clippings, and speeches, 1989-1991 and undated (Box-folder 56: 7)
  - Speech, undated (Box-folder 56: 8)
  - Articles by Diane Ravitch
    - American Scholar Article, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 9)
    - Chronicle in Higher Education Articles, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 10)
    - Educational Excellence Network (EEN), 1990 (Box-folder 56: 11)
    - The Key Reporter, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 12)
    - The Star Weekly, 1991 (Box-folder 56: 13)
    - The New York Newsday, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 14)
    - On excellent education, 1989 (Box-folder 56: 15)
    - Literature and History - Elementary Schools, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 16)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 17)
    - New York, 1990 (Box-folder 56: 18)
- Audio Cassettes, 1989-2003 and undated (Folder 57)
  - Undated and unidentified (Folder 57)
    Hazell's comments about Dinkins and the Jews are in middle of side III
  - A Conversation with Diane Ravitch, undated (Folder 57)
  - A Curriculum of Inclusion, undated (Folder 57)
  - R34 - JL - 2A, undated (Folder 57)
  - Eileen's originals, New York City, 1989 November 22 (Folder 57)